Is there any specific diet that you
recommend for people especially on TRT?
Something like keto diet or carnivore?
Is there something you prefer?
>> Sure. Sure. No, it's a great question. I
I could go you you might have to stop me
here. I can go about on about this for
for the whole the whole show. Um yeah,
so I think there's there's a few a few
general diet, you know, diet things here
and then the rest you kind of fill in
for your preference. Um, I like to see
everyone uh get a gram somewhere around
a gram per pound of body weight or ideal
or ideal healthy body weight, right? So,
if you have a lot of fat to lose and
you're 300 lbs, maybe you don't actually
need 300 grams. Maybe, you know, maybe
200 is your number. So, get get that in
protein per day. I think that's I think
that's a very important thing. Um, you
know, we talked about, you know, fats
earlier. So, I think making sure you're
getting some essential fatty acids. You
know, if you need to supplement that,
great. Um, but as far as fats go, you
know, somewhere around like.3 to point 6
grams per pound of body weight just for
general health and digestion and good,
you know, good functioning, I think
that's kind of the, you know, the
minimum amount of fat you should be
getting. And then you fill in the rest
with carbs, right? Carbs aren't the
devil. They're not evil. They're, you
know, their body's pref preferred fuel
source. Um, especially for someone
who's, you know, exercising hard and
wants to perform. I know someone will,
you know, someone will comment and say,
"I know a guy who's an ultramarathoner
or an elite powerlifter and he's, you
know, he's keto." That's great. You
know, it can it can work for some folks,
but in general, that's a that's a pretty
a pretty good way to do it. Um, but if
you have a preference towards eating a
little bit, you know, some some some
fattier foods, I think, as long as
you're hitting your caloric goal, um,
and you're meeting your protein
requirements, the rest of it is is is,
um, is negotiable. Things like keto or
carnivore,
um, it it can be tricky. It can be
tricky. they can skew some, you know,
some other health markers. Some people
it doesn't affect them at all. But I
think, you know, don't don't, you know,
don't fool yourself. I think it's some,
uh, you know, some magical thing to do.
Um, something like a carnivore diet, I
think, can be a nice thing as a uh as a
base for an elimination diet. And some
people need a gut reset. We take in a
lot of stuff. Even if you think you're
eating healthy good stuff, there's all
these additives and artificial
sweeteners and all this junk out there.
If you just want to give your gut a good
reset, give yourself, you know, three
months of just eating, you know, meat
and water and then, you know, maybe you
don't eat like that forever, but that
that'll change you. That'll fix your gut
and get you get you feeling pretty good.
>> Um, you know, but as far as, you know,
order of importance of things. I mean,
it's the, you know, the amount of
calories you're eating per day to meet
your goal, whether that's maintenance,
right? So, you're eating isocoric,
you're not trying to gain or lose
weight, right? Uh, if you want to be in
a, you know, you want to lose fat,
you're going to need to be in a deficit,
whatever that amount is. If you want to
gain some muscle, you probably had to be
in a little bit of a of a surplus. You
know, if you're a new beginner, you
could probably make those same gains at
maintenance for for a period of time.
And then the next, you know, the next
thing on the priority list is meeting
that uh you know, meeting that protein
goal. The rest the rest is negotiable.
>> Yeah, sure. I agree. I've always uh been
a proponent of flexible dieting. So, you
just
>> Sure.
>> eat what you want. Everything uh Yeah.
can be good if as long as if it's not
too much processed food. Try to avoid
that all additives and colorants and so
on. But uh yeah, just try to eat healthy
within your caloric uh restrictions,
your protein, your healthy fats.
Completely agree, Mike. That's what I
do.
>> Yeah, you do that. You do that 80% of
the time and you're doing better than
90% of the world. So,
>> yeah,
>> that extra bit of time, give yourself a
break. It's fine, right? Someone's
birthday and you want a piece of cake or
something, have the cake. It's okay. Oh,
yeah. It's easier than being too strict
and then fall off the boat.
>> Yeah.
>> Yeah. That's what I see a lot with
people who go with something like a like
a keto diet. They think this is the end
all be all and then they fall off their
wagon and what do they what do they
have?
>> Exactly.
>> Or they start finding keto treats and
now they're back up to being, you know,
eating too many calories anyway and the
whole plan falls apart. So,
>> yeah.
Hey,
hey, hey.